Nibil M S

Email: me@nibil.in / msnibil@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9495 41 2790

skype : sayyidnibil

Summary

I'm a Techno-Functional professional who started my career as the first employee of a startup after completion of my engineering course in Computer Science and Engineering. I started off as a Development Engineer, later on transitioning myself to a managerial role in the second tier leadership of the company while continuing my role as a Product Engineer in the company. In my 5-year stint with the startup, the company grew from 5 to 72 people. I have had the opportunity to experience the initial hiccups, the effective bootstrapping, external investment, acquisition and the growth of the company from multiple roles and perspectives.

I then moved on to Vogo and lead the development of SPARK, the world's first automated scooter rentals and helped in revamping the whole architecture.

Work Experience

Tech Lead (September 2016 to Present)

Vogo Automotive, Karnataka (www.vogo.in)

- Lead the development of SPARK, the world's first automated scooter rentals
- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Interact with COO and operations team and get inputs for the product.
- Do research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Interact with the design team (external) and convey the product requirements and make sure that the development is going on in the correct path and pace.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0
- Lead the development and do the backend revamp using Django Rest Framework.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

VP of Data Research (July 2014 to August 2016)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala

- Profoundis developed their flagship product (https://vibeapp.co) backed by a Human + Technology Hybrid engine which has been acquired by FullContact.
- As there was a need to grow Data Research as a function in the company, I gradually transitioned into a business role with client interactions.
- Directly reporting to Co-founder & Chief of Data Research, I led the operations side of data research function with the whole Data Research Team functionally reporting to me.
- Was also involved deeply in the recruitment, onboarding, training, performance appraisals as the team grew from 10 to 72.
- Part of the team that developed and maintained the internal Django webapp that augmented the Data Research process.
- Python language scripting.

Senior Product Engineer (July 2012 to June 2014)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala (www.profoundis.com)

- Joined Profoundis as the first employee after the first month of the company's inception.
- Reporting directly to the CTO of the company; responsible for the services side of Profoundis which was then bootstrapping.
- Worked with clients from Turkey, Middle East and the US including the likes of Vodafone which cumulatively earned over 100,000\$ for the company.
- Mostly worked with Python, Django, HTML and Javascript during this tenure.

Django Developer (August 2011 to June 2012)

As a prodigy of Mr. Kenneth Gonsalves (Chairman, Indian Python Software Society, 2010 2011)

- Worked on multiple projects including development and maintenance of Websites and Web applications in Python/Django.
- Clients included FIDA Kids (an NGO based out of Africa and India), Bamboo Banks (Ooty based hotel) and Ooty Golf Course.

Education

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering 2007-2011
 Vinayaka Missions University, Salem
- Higher Secondary Examination, March 2007
 Govt Higher Secondary School, Kumaranellur
- Technical High School Leaving Certificate, March 2005
 Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages and Frameworks:
 - Python, Django , Django Rest Framework
- Databases
 - PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Elasticsearch, MongoDB
- Operating Systems
 - GNU/Linux : both Redhat & Debian, Mac OS X, All Microsoft Windows Environments.

Management Skills

- Business sense with technology background.
- Leadership, Interpersonal and team skills
- Initiating, leading and optimizing day to day operations of a team at scale.
- Recruiting and building a team

Personal Information

Name : Nibil M S Sex : Male

Address : Needam, Trithala P.O, Palakkad-679534, Kerala, IN

Date of Birth : 06-10-1989 Marital Status : Married

Passport : Indian (#K3080682) Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil

Declaration

I hereby declare that all information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Nibil M S